# 大家好 今天家里沒菜啦 我出鎮上來買點菜
Hi everyone. I run out of food at home. So I'm coming to the town today to buy some.
# 現在鎮上都沒甚麼人啦
There are hardly any people in the town now.
# 大家都呆在家裡
Everybody stays at home.
# 大家沒事就呆在家 盡量少出門
Everybody stays at home and avoids coming if not really necessary.
# 今天在鎮上買了 面包哇 蘿蔔 淮山 (註︰淮山即山藥)
Today I've bought in the town some bread, and well, radish, yam,
# 淮山 豬肉 豬腳 豬肉 面
yam, pork, pork legs, pork, noodle,
# 洗髮水 沐浴露 還有奶茶 好多 一大堆
shampoo, shower gel, and milk tea. A lot of stuffs, a whole lot!
# 剛好路過兄弟的竹林 看一下有沒有竹笋挖 挖兩個竹笋來
We just pass by my buddy's bamboo forest. Let's see if there are any bamboo shoots, and get a couple of them.
# 到了竹林這裡 就在這上面一點
We've arrived at the bamboo forest. It's right up there.
# 你看 這邊好像沒有
Look! Here doesn't seem to be any.
# 這是兄弟家的竹林哦
This is my buddy's bamboo forest, you know.
# 他家的竹子太扣啦
His bamboos are too stingy.
# 一個笋都長不出來
There isn't even a single shoot.
# 我去
Let me,
# 隔壁家大嬸家看一下 她家有沒有 (註︰原字幕出錯，應該是︰「她家的竹林」
go to my neighbouring auntie and have a look at her bamboo forest.
# 看一下有沒有(竹笋)
and see if there are any (bamboo shoots).
# 軟啦~
I'm fatigue~
# 我要去前面看一下
I wanna have a look over there.
# 這邊竹林太硬啦
The soil is too hard here,
# 全是石頭 小石頭來的
all are rocks, tiny rocks.
# 不好挖
No good
# 前面 前面還有
There, over there
# 唉 有一個
Ay! Here's one!
# 爛掉啦
But it's broken.
# 那麼小的
It's so small.
# 很大哦
Ayo! It's big!
# 不小哦
It's not small.
# 爛掉啦
But it's broken.
# 誒 爛掉啦
Ey! It's broken.
# 不小心 一搞就搞爛啦
I broke it, before I noticed it.
# 好不容易挖一個都爛掉啦
It's a precious single bamboo shoot. But I've broken it.
# 嗯 還有一塊肉
Um! This part is still edible.
# 先放到這裡
Put it here first.
# 哎呀 有
Aya! Yeah!
# 你看 雙胞胎喲
Look! They're twins!
# 好小
They're so small.
# 那(麼)小一個
What a tiny little one.
# 這還一個小的
And here's another small one.
# 一下就挖到3個
So I got three at a time.
# 拿來炒咸菜
I'll have them fried with pickled mustard.
# 很好吃的哦 這個 竹笋炒咸菜
It tastes really good, bamboo shoots fried with pickled mustard.
# 好香呀 夠啦 夠啦
It smells really good! Enough, enough.
# 3個就夠啦 不要多
Three is enough. Don't take too many.
# 剩下的留給他們挖
The rest is left for them.
# 回去啦
Let's go back.